You're cute.
你真可爱
I know.
我知道
How old are you?
你几岁了？
15.
15岁
I'll give you pocket money.
我给你一些零用钱吧
Peep! Peep!
哔
Violation of Healthy Development of Youth Act!
违反青少年健康成长条例
Let's go.
我们走吧
Peep! Peep!
哔…
Woah…
哦…
I'm sorry. Are you okay?
对不起 没事吧？
Two weeks ago, on September 10th at five a.m.,
两周前 9月10日清晨五点
someone broke this mirror and we're looking for the culprit.
有人撞坏了这辆车的后视镜 我们在找犯人
Do you recognize this person?
请问你见过这个人吗？
It's a bit…
有点…
I don't know.
不知道
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
What language is that?
这是哪国语言？
You don't know, do you?
你一定听不懂吧？
I think he said good luck.
他应该是祝我好运吧
What? He seemed very angry--
什么？他好像很生气
I demand compensation! 700,000!
我要求赔偿 70万日圆
CLAIM FOR DAMAGES
（要求损害赔偿）
I'm sorry I took the request without asking you.
不好意思 我没问你就接了委托
But you can't refuse if it's someone you crashed into.
但我骑自行车撞上的对象要我帮忙 我总不好意思拒绝吧
Mr. Haneoka.
羽根冈律师
Yes?
有事吗？
Thank you for giving me a push the other day.
前几天你推了我一把 非常感谢
A-A push?
推…推一把？
I've decided to go out with Mr. Oba.
我决定要跟大庭先生交往了
Oh!
哦
Oh, really? Congratulations.
是吗？恭喜
Of course, I won't let this affect my--
当然 跟以前一样 绝对不会影响到工作…
Yeah, okay. I'm not worried.
没事…我不会担心
I know you always do your job perfectly.
我知道你一定会把工作做好的
YAMAMURO BUILDING
（山室大楼）
I saw this in a documentary.
我在纪录片里看到过这景象
Yamayoko kids, huh?
山横KIDS是吗？
Hello there.
大家好…
Excuse me, I'm a lawyer. Haneoka…
不好意思 我是律师 姓羽根冈…
I'm a lawyer, Haneo…
我是律师羽根…
Excuse me, do you know this person?
不好意思 请问你们知道这个人吗？
I'm a paralegal, Shoko Ishida.
我是律师助理 我叫石田硝子
Oh, excuse me.
不好意思…
Hello. I'm a lawyer, Hane--
你们好 我是律师羽根…
We're busy.
我们很忙
Of course. You do seem very busy, but--
当然 你们看起来的确很忙 不过…
No thanks.
不用了 谢谢…
Please be quiet.
请小声一点
-They're younger than you. -You want me to hear you out?
-她们年纪比你小… -要我听你们说吗？
Sorry?
什么？
Want me to hear you out?
我来听你们说吧？
Yes!
好
We're looking for this person.
我们正在找这个人
Buy me cigarettes in return.
但你们要先帮我买香烟
-What? -Cigarettes. Okay, sure.
-什么？ -香烟 好 我知道了
No! Lawyer Ethics.
不可以 请遵守律师伦理
I know, but--
我知道啦 可是…
I'm sorry, but we can't give you anything.
不好意思 我们无法提供你任何报酬
Oh, come on.
拜托
We've been told that this person might be the owner of this cafe.
听说这个人 很可能是这家咖啡厅的老板
Yeah. That outfit is definitely K.
看这穿着的确是K
Kei?
K？
The alphabet, "K."
英文字母K
Their real name is…
本名是…
I don't know.
不知道
Is it possible to meet this person?
有可能跟这个人见个面吗？
I can't get in touch either for almost two weeks now.
我也两个星期找不到人了
K tends to travel on a whim, so maybe that's why.
K常常一时兴起就跑出去旅行 大概是因为这样吧
Is it possible to give us K's contact information?
请问可以提供K的联络方式吗？
I don't mind.
是可以
Thank you.
不好意思 跟你借一下
I doubt it'll be useful though.
不过看样子是不会接电话
K seems to be close with the Yamayoko kids.
K好像跟山横的孩子相处得很不错
They all said K's like their leader.
他们都说K就像是首领一样
Yeah. It's like charity work.
就像是慈善事业
They come for advice and K feeds them here.
他们来寻求建议 K就提供他们饭吃
Because they're all broke.
因为大家都没钱
Have some tea.
请喝茶
Mom, he gave us tea.
妈妈 来喝茶吧
"The young people who hang out in the plaza
“位在丸来町山室大楼旁的广场
next to the Yamamuro Building in Marukicho are called Yamayoko Kids."
聚集了很多年轻人 大家就叫他们为山横KIDS
"The majority of them are minors."
其中大多数都未成年
"They dress in black-based clothes, which are called Landmine-style fashion."
打扮多半崇尚黑色为基调 也就是所谓的地雷系
"Some of them don't go home for various reasons
许多人因为各式各样的原因 有家归不得
and they stay in manga cafés and hotels instead."
有人就住在漫画网咖或是饭店里
"Many of the girls engage in 'jobs,' a hidden term for compensated dating,
许多女孩子以‘接案’为暗号 从事援助交际
to earn money for accommodation and food."
借此赚取食宿的费用
"This is becoming a serious social problem."
俨然形成严重的社会问题”
And K was their savior.
K就是这群孩子的救世主
I want to get in touch somehow.
有没有办法能找到人呢？
Hello, this is Haneoka.
喂 我是羽根冈
Help!
救命
Come to Marukicho now!
快到丸来町
Mifuyu!
美冬
Stay away from me!
不要碰我
Let me go!
放开我
Stop!
不要这样
No!
不要
I'll give you information on K! So, hurry!
我会给你K的情报 快点来
Sorry?
什么？
What are you doing?!
你在做什么？
Um, we'll be right over. Where are you?
我们马上过去 你在哪里？
Come on! We have to run. Hurry.
快点 我们得赶快逃 快点
Help!
救命
We're near the pedestrian bridge!
我们在丸来町的天桥附近
I can see the pedestrian bridge. Um…
我看到天桥了…
What else can you see?
还有什么地标吗？
Mifuyu, run!
美冬 快逃
-Are you alright? -Please get back.
-没事吧？ -请后退
The ambulance is here.
救护车已经到了
Please get back.
请后退
-Excuse me, coming through. -Sorry.
不好意思 我们要过去 -抱歉
-Please get back. -One, two, three!
-请后退 - 一、二、三
Mifuyu…
美冬…
Mifuyu? Mifuyu!
美冬？美冬
-Um, is… Is she… -I'm Miyabe.
-请问…她… -我姓宫部
Is she alright?
她不会有事吧？
Doctor.
医生
Here.
给你
Thank you.
谢谢
I'll have some now.
我要喝了
What happened earlier?
刚刚是怎么回事？
Nothing.
没事
Okay.
好吧
Water?
喝水吗？
Wha…
咦…
At this point, I can't tell if she'll regain consciousness.
现在还不知道她能不能恢复意识
We'll do our best,
我们会尽力救治
but please understand that she's in a critical condition.
不过她情况危急 这点还请两位理解
-Hey! -This is your fault!
-喂！ -都是你害的
-You were beating Mifuyu! -Okay, okay.
-你一直在打美冬吧 -好了
-What are you talking about? -Don't act dumb!
-在说什么？谁打人了？ -别给我装傻
You were trying to bring her back by beating her just now!
你刚刚为了把美冬带回去 也动手打了她吧
-Calm down. -No.
-冷静点 -并没有
I'm also upset about how things turned out.
事情变成这样 我也很难过
Let's calm down.
先冷静一下吧
-Calm down! -Wait!
-冷静点 -等等
-Hina, please calm down. -Hey!
-阳菜小姐 请冷静一下 -喂
It's over if you touch him.
你对他动手就输了
No violence. Okay?
不能使用暴力 知道吗？
What happened?
发生了什么事？
Forget it.
算了
Then why did you call--
那你为什么打电话给我…
I thought a lawyer could help!
我以为律师可以帮忙
It was pointless.
根本就没用
I'm sorry,
很抱歉
but we're not Superman.
但我们并不是超人
We can't just fly and come to the rescue.
没办法从空中飞过来救人
Superman?
超人？
You don't know Superman?
你不知道超人吗？
He has a mark on his chest. That "S"?
胸前有个什么…S吗？
Not now!
现在别扯这些
Forget it, old man.
算了 大叔
Why didn't you call the police?
为什么不去报警呢？
We're doing jobs.
我们在援交
There's no way we can call the police.
怎么可能去报警
Let's cool our heads for a moment.
我们先冷静一下吧
Yeah.
也对
Hang on. Where are you going?
等一下 你要去哪里？
Who cares.
管我呢
Why are you asking?
你问这个做什么？
As someone who practices law, I can't let a minor leave like this.
身为法律人 我不能让未成年人就这样离开
-It's none of your business. -It is!
-跟你没关系 -不
Now that we are involved, if you end up getting into trouble,
既然你联络过我们 要是你碰到了什么麻烦
we could be held responsible.
我们也会有责任
Huh?
什么？
I'll be in trouble, so come to my house.
这样我会有麻烦 请你到我家来
What? No.
什么？才不要
-I'll be in trouble. -No! I'm not going.
-这样我很困扰 -我才不去
She's really stubborn.
碰到这种情况 她会很固执
Why not?!
为什么？
Because I said so!
就是不要
You guys sound like you're fighting for the bill.
你们听起来好像在抢着付账
Barley tea?
要喝麦茶吗？
So, would it be possible to hold her father criminally responsible
因为她父亲在后面追着她跑
for her falling down
而导致她摔落楼梯
because he's the one who chased her?
有没有可能 以此追究他父亲的刑事责任？
That's difficult.
很难
It's possible if she fell while she was being chased.
如果是在追逐途中摔下去的 就可能有机会
But it was after she got away, right?
不过她是在甩开他之后 才发生意外的吧？
Yes.
对
According to the witness, she staggered and fell on her own.
报案人的说法是 她自己一个人跌倒摔下去的
I see. Then it'll probably be judged as no direct causal relationship there.
这样的话 很可能会判断为 没有直接的因果关系
That's what I thought.
我认为是这样
Thank you for taking the time.
谢谢你抽空跟我谈
No problem. Let's go for a drink again.
不会 我们再找时间去喝一杯吧
We can go to a public bath first.
先去公共澡堂泡个汤之类的
Yes. A public bath sounds great.
好 大众澡堂听起来很不错
Okay, bye.
好 先这样了
Goodbye.
我挂电话了
Bye.
好
PROSECUTOR YUNO HANEOKA
（检察官 羽根冈优乃）
That's a surprise.
吓到我了
I can't believe you're connected to my sister.
你居然跟我姐关系这么好 真不敢相信
Sister Yuno and I seem to get along well.
我跟大姐很合得来
Sister Yuno?
“大姐”？
By the way, are you sure?
话说 你确定吗？
I thought you don't take cases that don't pay.
不是不接没有钱赚的案子吗？
I'll allow myself to break my rule just this once.
这次我容许自己打破原则
She had another plate of fried rice.
她又吃了一盘炒饭
Why don't you eat here too?
你也在这里吃吧
You can stay here for a while.
请你先在这里住一阵子
Hina, where are your parents?
阳菜小姐 你的父母呢？
They're both dead.
他们都过世了
Do you know about the Child Guidance Center?
你知道儿少保护中心吗？
They have shelters for women--
也有女性专用的庇护所…
Stop it.
不用了
I don't trust grown-ups.
大人都不能信任
But…
可是…
You feel sorry for me?
你是在同情我吗？
I don't need pity or anything.
别这样 我又不可怜
I'll be fine.
我的事不重要
Just help Mifuyu.
你们救救美冬
I want to sue that guy.
我想要告那家伙
I'll sue him on her behalf.
我代替美冬告他
Mifuyu has been physically abused by her current father,
美冬的母亲在三年前再婚
whom her mother remarried to three years ago.
对象就是现在的父亲 他一直对美冬暴力相向
About a month ago, when she was severely beaten,
大约在一个月前 她又遭到毒打
she ran away from home and went to Yamayoko.
于是离家出走 加入山横
Didn't her mother protect Mifuyu?
美冬的母亲没有保护她吗？
She didn't seem to do anything. I guess she was afraid of him.
或许是对丈夫的暴力感到畏惧 她好像什么事也没做
Right. And…
对 还有…
you said you want to sue Mifuyu's father.
你说你想要告美冬的父亲
Did he do something to you too?
他对你做过什么吗？
No.
没有
Hmm. I see.
这样啊
This is difficult.
这就难办了
What?
什么？
Well, it has to be the victim herself.
必须是受害者本人才能提告
Why?
为什么？
Well…
这个嘛…
There are two ways to hold her father legally responsible.
要在法律上 追究她父亲的责任有两个办法
There's a civil trial and…
一个是民事诉讼
a criminal trial.
一个是刑事诉讼
Sir.
律师
Your stroke order is wrong.
你的笔画顺序错了
It doesn't matter.
不要紧
Yeah, not now.
对 现在是不要紧
As a general rule, you can only sue someone in a civil trial
原则上来说 民事诉讼一定要
if the intention of the person affected can be confirmed.
确认受害者本人的意愿 否则无法提告
So, only Mifuyu can sue him?
那就只有美冬能告吗？
What about her mother?
她妈妈呢？
She's a minor, so her mother can sue him as her legal representative.
她还未成年 母亲是法定代理人 这样就能提告了吧？
I intend to ask her.
我会想办法劝她
But she seems to be under his thumb.
不过她好像对丈夫言听计从
It won't be easy.
应该不容易劝
And at criminal trial…
至于刑事诉讼
we judge the case that police--
是要有警方采取行动的案件…
I don't get it. You're saying I can't sue him?
我不懂 就是不能告的意思吗？
That's what I'm explaining!
我现在不就是在解释吗？
Why do you keep interrupting?
为什么要一直打断我？
I don't care how. Just do something about him!
我不管怎样 想办法对付那家伙
Mifuyu really is being abused.
美冬真的遭到虐待了
"Do you have proof of that?"
“你有证据吗？”
That's what they'll say.
他们会这样问你
We don't doubt you.
我们并没有怀疑你
We need proof to judge her father in a court of law.
但要以法律制裁她父亲就需要证据
Presumption of innocence. Being suspicious isn't enough to punish someone.
我叫无罪推定 光是有嫌疑 是没办法判刑的
What?
什么？
It's to protect an innocent person from being falsely charged.
这是为了预防无辜之人被起诉 也不会因此而造成冤案
You mean, I can't do anything about him?
所以我们就拿她爸没招了？
So, sometimes…
所以有时候…
Even the real bad guys are protected.
连真正的坏人也会受到保护
What the hell is that?
这算什么？
Hina, take a bath before you go to bed.
阳菜 上床睡觉前要先洗澡
Hina.
阳菜
Geez.
真是的
After all, lawyers can only work within the law.
律师只能在法律的范围内采取行动
We're not Superman.
毕竟我们并不是超人
Clouds will be spreading across Chugoku, Shikoku and Kyushu regions tomorrow.
明天在中国、四国和九州岛地区 是多云的天气
Please beware of sudden showers.
可能会有临时阵雨 请多加注意
FOR HINA.
（阳菜 请不要客气）
Temperatures will be cooler than this morning in Eastern Japan…
接下来是气温 东日本早上的气温 会比今天早上还要低…
I'm counting on you! Seriously!
我就拜托你了 真的
Hey, if you can speak Japanese, can't you just…
既然你会讲日语 一开始…
Kanami Kuwata's body was found buried in a vacant lot in Kutsuna City.
桑田佳那美小姐的遗体 被发现埋在忽那市的空地里
A 19-year-old boy was arrested on suspicion of corpse abandonment.
一名19岁的少年 以弃尸罪嫌遭到逮捕
Ms. Kuwata was…
过世的桑田小姐是…
It's K, who died.
是K 她死掉了
What?
什么？
She was known as K, who was popular amongst the youngsters…
她人称K 很受年轻人追捧
-K was a woman? -She posted on social media…
-K是女的？ -她在社交媒体上发贴…
I thought it was a man.
我还以为是男的
Messages such as "Let's build a new life together."
发过“一起打造新生活”之类的消息
The arrested boy admits to the charge and that they were in a power struggle.
据被捕的少年供认 是因为争夺权力而与对方发生冲突
Ms. Kuwata was also involved in the mediation of prostitution and…
遗体被发现的桑田小姐 还参与了卖淫…
She was mediating it?
她是中间人吗？
…caught up in the conflict.
因而卷入利益冲突
Her estimated time of death is the afternoon of September 9th
推测死亡时间为9月9日下午
and it is believed that she was buried after death.
桑田小姐应该是死后才遭到掩埋
The police are…
警方…
They said she was killed on September 9th.
据称她是9月9日遇害
The day K was caught on camera was September 10th, right?
行车记录仪 是在9月10日拍到K吧？
Who is this?
这个人是谁啊？
Are you hiding something?
你有隐瞒什么事吗？
No.
没有
Do you know something about that--
刚刚那起案件 你知道些什么吗？
No!
不知道
-I don't. -Hey.
-等一下 -我不知道
Hey, you're a minor.
未成年人不能抽烟
Give it to me.
把东西给我
Just tell us.
别隐瞒了 告诉我们吧
The K in that video footage…
行车记录仪拍到的K…
That's Mifuyu.
是美冬
What?
什么？
She was in disguise?
她假扮的？
Mifuyu and I also…
我和美冬
asked K to refer us to clients
在没钱的时候
whenever we ran out of money.
会请K帮我们介绍客人
But she takes 70 percent as a referral fee.
但是介绍费她要抽七成
-70 percent? -That much?
-七成？ -这么多？
When we complained,
我们跑去跟K抱怨
she secretly filmed us during our jobs
她就在我们援交的时候偷拍视频
and she threatened to post those videos online.
威胁着要把视频发到网络
We hadn't seen her for about two weeks.
大概两个星期前 她就开始不见人影
So, Mifuyu pretended to be K and snuck into the café
为了拿回装了我们视频的记忆卡
to retrieve the SD card of the videos.
美冬就假扮成K 偷偷溜进店里
K? Is that you, K?
K？是你吗 K？
But she failed. So we ran and…
但是失败了 就在慌忙逃走的时候…
Meet at 7-Eleven!
在7-11便利店碰面
She hit the car.
她撞到了那辆车
Thank you for telling us.
谢谢你告诉我们
Unfortunately, if Mifuyu was the one who damaged the car,
非常遗憾 如果撞坏车子的人是美冬
she would have to pay the repair costs.
那她就要赔偿修车费用了
-What? -But she is a minor.
-什么？ -但是她未成年
And she is hospitalized, so her parents will be the ones paying.
而且正在住院 赔偿的人就变成她的父母了
Really?
是这样吗？
So now, we have business with Mifuyu's parents. Don't we?
这样的话 就跟美冬的父母扯上关系了
Yes, that's right.
没错
We can visit her house and ask them various questions!
我们就可以登门拜访 好好把事情问个清楚了
Exactly. If we happen to find proof
没错 如果在索赔的过程中
of her father's violence in the course of claiming compensation,
刚好发现父亲施暴的证据
we can't ignore it.
那可没办法视而不见
Yes. We must demand appropriate compensation.
到时候就得好好处理了
Huh?
什么？
Oh.
啊
700,000.
70万日圆
Yes. The car body is also damaged, so the door needs replacing.
对 车身有刮伤 车门要整个换掉
Did Mifuyu really do this in the first place?
是说 把车撞坏的人真的是美冬吗？
Her friend who was with her has testified.
这是当时跟她在一起的朋友 提供的证词
She's probably a runaway too, right?
她一定也离家出走了吧？
I wonder if her testimony is reliable.
那种人提供的证词可信吗？
Please come in.
请进
Slippers!
拖鞋
They run away from home due to reasons they can't control.
她其实是因为不得已的苦衷 才会离家出走
I don't mean to be rude, but did Mifuyu have a reason like that?
恕我失礼 美冬是不是有类似的苦衷 才没办法待在家里呢？
What is this?
现在是怎样？
You're just a clerk, aren't you?
你只不过是个职员吧？
No. A paralegal is a clerk who has the required knowledge of law--
并不是 律师助理 是要具备法律知识的职员
I am talking to him, a lawyer.
我是在跟律师讲话
This isn't the time for you to speak.
还轮不到你开口
To be frank,
恕我直言
isn't it because of your violence?
原因就是你对她施暴吧？
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
I'm sorry. Hey.
不好意思 等一下
-Mr. Haneoka. -Yes?
-羽根冈律师 -是？
You can sue me or do whatever you want.
你想告就去告吧
Hey.
嘿
That's not what I had in mind.
事情发展跟我想的不一样
I was planning to break him slowly.
原本是要慢慢突破他的防备的
I'm sorry.
对不起
Seeing him in person just…
看到他在我面前就忍不住…
I get it, but still.
我也懂你的心情
As long as we're working on the car case, Mifuyu is our client's enemy.
可是既然承接了车身受损的委托 美冬小姐就是委托人的敌方
Right?
对吧？
If we work for her, it'll be a conflict of interest.
为她采取行动会造成利益冲突
But I want to help.
但是我想要帮她们
Both Mifuyu and Hina.
美冬小姐和阳菜小姐
Well, yeah. But…
没错 不过…
Last night, before going to sleep, Hina told me a little bit about herself.
昨晚睡觉前 阳菜小姐跟我说了一些她的事
She's been in Yamayoko for two years now
待在山横两年了
and that she didn't bother making any friends.
一直没有交到朋友
But she met Mifuyu last month
不过 她在上个月遇见了美冬小姐
and they hit it off because they both suck at opening rice ball wrappers.
两个人都很不会拆饭团的包装 结果一拍即合
Mifuyu is the first friend she made. She said that so happily.
她很开心地说 美冬小姐是她交到的第一个朋友
She opened up to me, even if it's a little.
她对我稍微敞开了心扉
This could be a chance for them to change their lives.
这说不定是美冬小姐和阳菜小姐 改变人生的机会
So, I strongly felt that I wanted to help.
就算只有一点点也好 我很想要帮她们的忙
Their lives?
说什么人生？
That's an exaggeration.
太夸张了吧
I think…
人生…
it only takes a little for a life to change.
会因为一些微不足道的小事而改变
PUSH BUTTON TO WALK
（按钮式红绿灯）
I witnessed a traffic accident.
我目睹了一场车祸
BAR EXAMINATION VENUE
（司法考试会场）
Please move away!
麻烦让一下
Are you alright?
没事吧？
Right in front of me, a woman…
一名女性就在我面前…
I was on my way to my first bar exam.
就在我第一次参加司法考试的途中
I did take the exam after that,
之后我还是进考场了
but my mind was blank.
但是脑中一片空白
Since then, every year…
在那之后 每年…
it comes back to me every time I take the exam.
去考试的时候都会想起这件事
Is that why…
所以才…
you've failed four times?
考挂了四次？
Yes.
对
I really think that
我真的认为
people's lives can change in a flash.
人生要发生改变 只是一瞬间的事
When there are accidents or incidents, it's not just victims, offenders
发生意外或案件的时候 不是只有加害者和受害者
and their families.
不是只有他们的家人
But it also instantly changes the lives of those who witness it.
连刚好目睹事件的人 人生也会在一瞬间改变
Those people in Yamayoko, Hina and Mifuyu.
那些待在山横的人 阳菜小姐和美冬小姐
I think it's the same for them.
应该也是一样的
Maybe a little encounter with something
或许只是因为遇到了一些小事
has put them in an environment they didn't wish for.
结果就沦落到身不由己的境地
If that's the case, this encounter with us may change their lives a little too.
这样的话 或许因为遇到了我们 多少也能改变她们的人生
Don't you think so?
你不这么认为吗？
You're right.
你说得对
But…
只是…
I won't get my hopes up.
我不会抱太多期待
With this job,
这份工作
too much of it ends in disappointment.
有太多期望落空的例子了
AO OBA
（大庭苍生）
-Hello. -Ishiko.
-喂 -学姐
I got a contract on my first day!
我第一天去跑业务就拿到合约了
Wow, congratulations.
恭喜
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, I forgot to say that it's me, Oba.
我忘记说了 我是大庭
-I know. -Here you go.
-我知道 -为您上菜
Let's celebrate soon.
找时间帮你庆祝吧
Yay!
太好了
Here's your yakitori platter and…
这是串烧拼盘…
Is this a bad time? Are you still working?
方便讲话吗？你还在工作吗？
-Um, yes. -This is a rolled omelet.
-嗯 对 -这是煎蛋卷
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I'll have a toast by myself for today.
那我今天就一个人先干杯了
I usually only drink one can, but I think I'll drink two today.
平常都喝一瓶 今天就喝两瓶吧
Mr. Oba.
大庭先生
May I come over to your place?
我可以去你家吗？
Sure. What?
可以 咦？
Huh?
啊？
-Good evening. -Hello.
-晚安
I wanted to pick you up.
我正要去接你
I'm sorry.
不好意思
No worries.
不会
You didn't get lost?
没有迷路吗？
No.
没有
Come in.
请进
Thank you.
打扰了
Sorry about the sudden visit.
不好意思 突然跑来
No problem.
没关系
I'm just surprised that our first date is here.
只是第一次约会就来家里 吓了我一跳
I mean, I'm completely fine with it.
我是完全没问题
But are you?
但你可以吗？
My rule is, I can enter a man's house if I'm in a relationship with him.
我的原则是如果在交往 就可以进到对方的家里 没问题
Please sit.
请坐
Thank you.
谢谢
It really is clean.
真的蛮干净的
But will I be able to help you?
但我帮得上忙吗？
It's this.
关于这点
I was hoping you could work your magic as a techie.
我希望靠大庭先生对电脑的知识
-When, Hina? -I have to go now.
-阳菜 几点开始？ -现在就得过去了
Now?
现在？
-HOW ABOUT 20,000? -OKAY. TIME AND PLACE?
（-两万日圆可以吗？ -好 时间和地点呢？）
-Good luck. -Is he in heat?
-加油 -他欲火焚身了吗？
I'm gonna go. Bye.
那我走了 拜拜
Ow…
痛…
People think Mifuyu's father is a good and earnest man.
大家都觉得美冬小姐的父亲 是工作认真的好人
He does seem sensible.
确实给人稳重的印象
But there's a bar he often goes to after work.
不过有一家他下班常去的酒吧
His reputation isn't good there.
他在那里的风评不太好
He's the typical, weak against the strong and strong against the weak kind of guy.
他是那种典型欺软怕硬的人
So he acts very arrogant towards store staff, women and young people.
所以对店员、女性和年轻人 态度都非常傲慢
The type I hate the most.
我最讨厌这种人了
If we dig deeper, we might find something useful.
从这方面进行调查 或许可以让他露出马脚
So you didn't give up on those girls.
你还是不死心 非要帮她们
Of course not.
那还用说吗？
I've said this many times already, but who do you think I am?
我已经说过多少次了 你到底把我当成什么了？
I got something too. Look.
我也有收获 你看
Oh?
哦？
The video wasn't very clear, so I asked for Mr. Oba's help.
原本的视频不是很清楚 所以我去找大庭先生帮忙
-Oh, that's why… -Huh?
-所以才… -什么？
Nothing. Continue.
没事 请继续
She has a bruise.
你看她这里有一片瘀伤
Right? Wouldn't this prove that Mifuyu is the one who damaged the car?
这不就能证明撞坏车子的人 是美冬小姐吗？
Not bad, Ishiko.
不错呀 石子小姐
-However… -Yes?
-不过… -是？
This was two weeks ago.
那是两周前的事
I'm sure the bruise is gone now
现在瘀血应该已经退了
and we also need evidence to prove she had that bruise two weeks ago.
要能证明美冬小姐身上 在两周前有这个瘀伤
What about that video?
那个视频呢？
Huh?
什么？
The one K secretly filmed.
K偷拍的视频
There are naked shots of us.
拍到我们的裸体了
Are you serious? They were in the drawer.
不会吧？之前放在抽屉里的
I guess the police seized them.
被警方扣押了吧
Can't we borrow it? We're the ones in the video.
不能去借出来吗？视频拍到我们了
They will be used as evidence for a homicide.
应该是被当成杀人案的证据了
I doubt they'll lend it to us so easily.
不是那么简单能借出来的
-What's up! -Who's this?
-喂 -谁啊？
Hina, guess what?
阳菜 听我说
Who are you?
你谁啊？
It's Kizaki. We've met at K's cafe several times.
我是木崎啦 我们在K的店里见过几次
Right.
是
The café's been closed down.
那间店关掉了
So I'm low on money. Help me out.
所以我现在很缺钱 帮帮我吧
Help you?
帮你？
Yeah, you know the SD card that K kept?
对 K留着的记忆卡
I have it now.
现在在我手上
What?
什么？
You don't want this to be shared online, right?
你不希望这个视频流出去吧？
To cut the story short, I'll be replacing K now.
简单说 我现在接替K的位置了
Hey! Are you listening?!
喂听到没？
Yes, I've been listening very closely.
有 听得非常清楚
I'm Haneoka. The lawyer who came to visit the café the other day.
我是先前到店里拜访过的律师羽根冈
You just threatened her, didn't you?
你刚刚完全就是在威胁她吧？
This is intimidation under Article 222--
这触犯了刑法第222条恐吓罪
S-Sorry. I'm sorry.
对…对不起
No point apologizing. This conversation is being recorded too.
道歉也没用 这通电话我已经录音了
You must first reflect on what you said
你要先反省刚刚的发言
and swear you won't engage in criminal activities in the future.
并发誓今后不会再参与犯罪
And hand over that video to us right now.
然后立刻把你手上的视频交给我们
Yes, I swear. I'll give you the data too.
是 我不会再做任何事 视频也会交给你
-You didn't make a copy, did you? -No, I--
-你应该没有备份吧？ -没有…
If you did, you'll be in big trouble.
要是有的话 事情可就严重了
No, I didn't. For real.
没有啦 我说真的
I'm in front of K's café--
我在K的店前面…
I'll bring it to you right now!
我立刻送过去
Okay, then. Be careful.
好 那就请你路上小心
See? This is what I'm capable of.
看到没？事情交给我 轻松就解决了
That's right. He gets things done when he has to.
没错 该他表现时 还是会把事情处理好的
His socks may be mismatched, but still.
虽然两只脚穿了不同的袜子
Old man, are you actually a klutz?
大叔 你该不会笨手笨脚吧？
No, I am not a klutz.
没有 大叔没有笨手笨脚
This is a trend, right?
这是现在流行的穿法 你们不知道吗？
No.
不知道
-Anyway… -He changed the subject.
-先不说这个了… -马上转移话题
If we have the video, we're good for the trial?
只要拿到视频 官司就没问题了吧？
Yes.
是
You mean the trial for the car, right?
这个官司是指车子吧？
What about the abuse?
那美冬被打的事呢？
Leave it to us.
包在我身上
If all goes well, we may be able to win both battles
如果一切顺利 车子和家暴两个案子
for the car and assault.
可以一起获得胜利
Right.
就是啊
After watching this footage, you are certain that this person
也就是说 从行车记录仪的视频来看 你能确定这个人
is not Ms. Mifuyu Azuma. Yes?
并不是东美冬小姐？
That's right. I'm sure this is not my daughter.
对 这绝对不是我女儿
I believe we are not liable for the compensation.
我认为我们没有赔偿的责任
That'll be all.
我问完了
Plaintiff counsel.
接下来换原告律师
Yes. Let me get to the point.
好 立刻进入正题
Please take a look at this photo, Exhibit 11.
请看第11号证据的照片
This is an enlarged image of the dashcam footage.
这是行车记录仪视频的放大截图
This person has a large bruise. Do you recognize it?
这个人手臂上有大片的瘀血 你对这有印象吗？
Not at all.
完全没有
This was recorded on September 10th,
这是在9月10日拍到的
which was six days after your daughter ran away from home--
那天是你女儿离家出走后六天…
I don't remember the date.
我不记得是哪一天
You don't remember the date your daughter disappeared from your home.
你不记得女儿是哪一天离家出走的
Well, I guess that's how it is.
原来如此 就是这样吧
By the way, on September 4th, the day she left,
顺带一提 她离家的那天是9月4日
did Mifuyu have any bruises on her body?
美冬小姐的身上当时有瘀血吗？
I wouldn't know. I don't look at my daughter's body.
我不知道 我不会去看女儿的身体
Then please look at the footage, Exhibit 14.
接着请看第14号证据的视频
This was recorded on September 7th and Mifuyu is in it.
这是9月7日的录像 里面拍到了美冬小姐
Let me play it.
我要播放了
Hey, how did you get that bruise?
你那个瘀伤是怎么回事？
It looks bad.
太严重了吧
That guy did it.
是那家伙干的
That guy?
那家伙？
I don't even want to say his name, so "that guy."
我连他的名字都不想提 就是那家伙
That guy's been beating me for years.
我已经被那家伙打好几年了
The appraisal result showed that this bruise on her shoulder and back
鉴定结果显示 这片从肩膀到背部的瘀伤
is identical to the bruise on the person in the dashcam footage we saw earlier.
跟先前行车记录器拍到的人 身上的瘀伤形状一致
The person in the latter footage is your daughter, correct?
后面那段视频拍到的人 是你女儿没错吧？
Yes.
对
By the way, do you know when, where and how
顺带问一下 这片瘀血是何时、何地 怎么出现的
she got those bruises?
您知道吗？
Objection. This has nothing to do with this case.
反对 这个问题与本案无关
Plaintiff counsel, is there a relevance to this case?
原告律师 这个问题与本案有何关联性？
If her father knows about the bruises,
如果父亲知道瘀血的事
it further proves the identity of the person who damaged the car as Mifuyu.
就更能证明撞坏车子的人 与美冬小姐是同一个人
Objection overruled. Please continue your question.
反对无效 请继续提问
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Mifuyu was talking about the person who assaulted her as "that guy."
视频中 美冬小姐 提到了对她施暴的人
Could you confirm if "that guy" is you, Mr. Azuma?
她口中的“那家伙” 就是指东先生 没错吧？
Why would you think that?!
为什么会有这种想法？
You can't assume that it's me just because she said, "That guy."
光凭她说了“那家伙”就认定是我 未免太不合理了吧
Your honor, these questions have nothing to do with this case!
审判长 后面这些问答都与本案无关
Indeed. Haven't you asked enough questions about the bruise?
确实 关于瘀伤的问题 应该已经问够了吧？
No more questions.
我没问题了
The plaintiff demands compensation from Ms. Mifuyu Azuma
原告基于以上论点 向东美冬小姐寻求赔偿
and we believe her parents also have the obligation to pay.
认为她的监护人 也就是双亲 有赔偿的义务
Fine. I'll take responsibility.
我知道了 我会负起责任
Plaintiff, please return to your seat.
原告请回座
Understand?
可以吧？
Yes.
是
You did a great job! Thank you!
你做得太好了 律师 谢谢你
Okay. Um, you need to be quiet.
好 请保持肃静
So, you won that trial?
刚刚的官司打赢了吗？
The verdict isn't out yet. But by the judge's reaction, most likely.
判决结果还没出来 但是看法官的反应 十拿九稳了
Right.
没错
But he didn't admit to the assault.
但他没有承认施暴吧
It all begins now.
好戏现在才要开始
Now, let's keep up the pace.
那就不要松手 马上进行下一步吧
Hey, hurry up and bring another glass.
喂 赶快再帮我倒一杯
I'm sorry. It'll be ready soon.
抱歉 我马上帮您准备
That guy's been beating me for years.
我已经被那家伙打好几年了
Isn't it because of your violence?
原因就出在你这个爸爸对她施暴吧？
Could you confirm if "that guy" is you, Mr. Azuma?
她口中的“那家伙” 就是指东先生 没错吧？
They all piss me off.
他们全都让我很不爽
-Good evening. -Hello.
-晚上好 -你好
Welcome.
欢迎光临
-Excuse us. -Hi.
-不好意思 我坐隔壁 -你好
-I'll have a highball. -Make that two.
-威士忌苏打… -两杯
Sure.
好的
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让您久等了 抱歉
Man. What a long day, huh? Oba?
今天很辛苦吧 大庭？
Yes. I completely agree with you, Manager.
是啊 我完全同意 部长
You're going to act as a senior and junior at work.
两位的角色是公司里的前辈和晚辈
You're both married with children.
两位都结了婚 有小孩
After you sit next to him, start with small talk.
坐在他旁边之后 就开始闲聊
Be natural. Okay?
表现得自然一点 可以吗？
Hurry. We're waiting for you.
快点 等你贴好
But sir, kids really are cute. Aren't they?
但是前辈 小孩子真的好可爱啊
Four years old, right? That's the cutest age.
你家的现在四岁对吧？ 这个年纪最可爱了
"Daddy."
“爸爸”
She rushes towards me saying "Daddy."
会叫着“爸爸” 跑来迎接我
"Daddy, daddy," huh?
会叫“爸爸” 对吧？
Will you hear me out?
你愿意听我说吗？
Me?
什么？
It shouldn't be too strange to talk to him if you're in a bar.
在酒吧里跟他搭话 应该不会太唐突才对
Don't let him refuse and start talking.
别让他有拒绝的机会 开门见山
You see, my daughter calls me "that guy."
我女儿都叫我“那家伙”
She's a third-year in junior high.
她现在上高三
Wouldn't that make you mad?
你不觉得很气人吗？
That is a problem indeed.
那的确是个问题
Right? Maybe she's looking down on me.
对吧？她是不是瞧不起我啊？
She ignores him when he talks to her and says stuff like "Get lost!"
前辈跟她讲话的时候也不回 还会叫他“走开”
I see…
这样啊…
Don't you think it's terrible? I mean, I'm her parent.
你不觉得很过分吗？我是她爸
They're both in the living room,
明明都在客厅里
but she would ask his wife to pass on the message to him. Right?
他女儿还会叫夫人传话 “你去跟那家伙说” 对吧？
Yeah.
没错
Isn't it infuriating?
太令人气愤了吧？
That really is annoying.
那样的确很气人
When he takes the bait, get him to talk about specific incidents.
等他上钩之后 想办法套出更具体的证词
You get it, right? I've been feeling so frustrated!
你懂吧？我心情很郁闷
I understand. My daughter calls me "that guy" too.
我懂 我女儿也叫我“那家伙”
She doesn't see me as a parent.
根本不把我当成是她爸爸
I'm taking care of a stepdaughter, but she's messing with me.
我老婆的拖油瓶 我好心照顾她 她却完全不把我当回事
We'll use the term "that guy" as an icebreaker.
“那家伙”的发言 只是想趁机让他卸下心防
From here, we'll get to the core.
接下来就要一口气直捣核心
How should we handle children like that?
对付这样的小孩 要怎么做比较好？
If scolding them doesn't work, you gotta do what you gotta do.
如果骂也没有用 就只能那样做了
What do you mean?
那样做是什么意思？
Hit her.
直接揍一顿啊
Hit her?
用揍的？
Beating her is the only way to shut her up.
只能用揍的来叫她闭嘴了
Women can't win against men anyway.
反正女人原本就打不过男人
Just hit her.
直接揍就对了
Will that make her obedient?
这样她就会乖乖听话了吗？
Yeah. She'll do whatever you say if you beat her to a pulp.
对 揍得她鼻青脸肿 就会乖乖听话了
Do you actually beat your daughter?
你真的会揍你女儿吗？
No.
不
It's not just a beating.
那不只是揍
To me, it's discipline.
要我的说的话 那是管教
I've been beating her this whole time.
我常常揍我女儿
But I do it as a necessary discipline as a parent.
不过那是因为我身为父亲
So when she goes out into society, she doesn't embarrass herself.
不能让孩子出社会后丢人现眼 这是必要的管教
That's why I beat her.
所以我才会揍她
I see.
这样啊
That's criminal assault.
这是暴力犯罪
Huh?
什么？
Right. I think you've crossed the line.
对啊 这样很过分吧
What is this?
为何突然说这些？
Listen up!
听好了
Even if you're her father, you can still get charged with assault and battery.
就算你是她父亲 动用暴力就是犯罪 只要她有受伤 你就触犯了伤害罪
That's right!
没错
Under Penal Code Article 2…
伤害罪是刑法第2…
200…
200…
Huh?
咦？
-Um… -Huh? You're kidding, right?
-那个… -不会吧…
200…
第200…
Article 204!
第204条
Oh…
喔…
Who are you?
你是谁啊？
Have you forgotten about the paralegal, who isn't a lawyer?
你不记得我了吗？ 我不是律师 只是个律师助理
Under Penal Code Article 204, anyone who inflicts physical harm
根据刑法第204条 伤害他人身体者
will be imprisoned for up to 15 years or pay a fine of up to 500,000 yen.
可判处15年以下有期徒刑 或是50万日圆以下的罚金
Mr. Azuma, I believe your violence to Mifuyu
东先生 你对美冬小姐的暴行
will be considered a battery charge.
已经构成了伤害罪
That's an exaggeration.
哪有那么夸张
I heard the whole conversation you had,
你刚刚一连串的发言 我听得很清楚
so I will testify that you have been beating her.
我可以证明你曾经施暴
I will too!
我也可以
Me too!
我也是
I was only kidding. It'll be no good as evidence.
我只是在开玩笑 这种事也能当证据吗？
-Now, now… -I've also recorded it just in case.
-等一下… -以防万一 我也录音了
This and the video will be enough.
加上那个视频 证据已经很充分了
I'll see you in the trial.
我们就法庭上见吧
Huh? What trial?
说什么法庭？
The car trial is already--
车子的官司已经…
Someone has come forward to sue you for assault and battery.
有人要以暴力伤害为理由 对你提出告诉
No way. My wife?
不是吧 我老婆？
The lawyer in charge is on the way to see her right now.
现在负责的律师已经过去见她了
Come in. Hi.
请进 你好
To see Ms. Mifuyu Azuma, who has filed the lawsuit.
去见要提告的东美冬小姐
It's very nice to meet you. Thank you very much.
初次见面 非常感谢
She regained consciousness yesterday.
她昨天就恢复意识了
No, it's my pleasure.
不会 这是我的荣幸
Introduce me, will you?
你怎么没有好好介绍呢？
I was just doing that.
我正想要介绍啊
They didn't tell me!
我怎么没听说
That's because she refused to have them notify you.
因为她拒绝跟你联络
What?
什么？
I'm glad we believed she'd wake up and prepared beforehand.
还好我们一直相信她会醒过来 事先采取了必要行动
Your earlier statements, Mifuyu's testimony and the video of her bruises
你刚刚的发言 加上美冬小姐的证词 以及瘀伤的视频
should prove that you have been physically abusing her on a daily basis.
应该就能证明你经常对美冬小姐施暴
We will proceed to sue you with a civil case.
接下来我们会对你提起民事诉讼
Additionally, Mifuyu will be filing a report with the police,
另外 美冬小姐也打算报警
so you'll eventually be arrested.
之后你应该会遭到逮捕吧
Please be prepared.
请做好心理准备
That'll be all.
我说完了
The food truck compensation has been settled, right?
餐车的赔偿问题已经解决了吧？
Yes. Regarding that case, the girls will…
对 关于这件事 她们会…
I'll work and pay it myself.
我会自己工作赚钱来赔偿
She did all this for my sake as well,
美冬当初那样做也是为了我
so I'll pay too.
我也会一起赔偿
But the client wanted the payment in a lump sum,
不过委托人希望能一次付清
so I lent the money to Mifuyu as a friend.
所以我以友人的身份 把钱借给美冬小姐
Of course, the client is aware of the process.
当然这件事委托人也接受了
We've paid the full amount and he's withdrawn the lawsuit.
我们付了全额 他也撤告了
You paid for her?
您帮她垫钱了？
I know my actions may be frowned upon as a lawyer.
我知道身为律师 这不是值得称许的行为
But as a grown-up, I just had to.
但是身为大人 总不能放着不管
Are you sure you want to sue your father?
你真的要告你爸爸吗？
I'm not running anymore. I'll fight.
我不要再逃避了 我要挺身奋战
The number of runaway minors taken into custody has tripled in a year…
因离家出走而接受辅导的未成年人 人数几乎是去年的三倍
Midnight downtown has become their place.
深夜的闹区成为他们的去处
Understanding their background might be the first step to
了解他们的背景 或许才能在检讨支援方式上
learning how we can help them.
迈出第一步
SHELTER AND SUPPORT CENTER
（都民庇护支援中心）
See you. Old man, old lady.
再见了 大叔 大婶
O-Old lady?
大…大婶？
Welcome to this side.
欢迎你加入
Shall the old man and old lady go home?
大叔和大婶要回去了吗？
Who are you calling old lady?
你叫谁大婶？
Hi.
大家好
Oh, please stay seated.
请坐…
Today I've gathered the managers, who I think are close to me.
今天 我邀请了 很要好的各个经营者莅临现场
I hope I'm not the only one who thinks that.
或许只有我觉得很要好
And they have chosen and brought the rest of you here
能干的他们挑选了前途无量的员工
because you have a promising future.
就是在场的各位
President Tone!
刀根社长
I'm excited about our future.
未来真是令人期待
Expand your horizontal network today
今天就尽量扩展各位的横向网络
and while we're at it, let's build Japan's future too!
一起开创日本的未来吧
Oh, thanks.
多谢
Seriously, the way to success is really easy.
其实 成功的方法很简单
Just don't give up until you succeed.
就是成功之前绝对不要放弃
Just kidding.
说说而已
Okay, then. Let's have a toast.
那就一起来干杯吧
My restaurant is on a restaurant guide website.
我的店被放到美食网上了
It's a hidden gem.
地点隐秘就是卖点
This is an infringement of goodwill.
这构成了损害商誉
They have the right to freedom of expression
发文者有言论自由
and the viewers have the right to know.
浏览的用户也知情权
She practically wore her life out for you.
她会这么早死都是爸害的
There's no precedent that overturned a case like this.
从过往的判例来看 这种情况是不可能翻案的
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰